Outta my way, losers!
That dumbass!
Shit! Somebody stop him!
Stop! Stop!
We aren't allowed to use the court right n-
Huh?
Look out!
Are you all right, Yoshino?!
Wait! We shouldn't move her around!
Shit. This is a disaster.
Hang in there, Yoshino!
Yoshino?
Nurse's Office
Okay. That should do it.
You've only suffered a slight concussion.
If you go home and get
a proper day of rest, then you'll be fine.
That's a relief.
What kind of attitude is that?!
She still got hurt just the same!
The basketball team has been causing
way too many problems lately!
You need to quit ruining things for the rest of us!
Mai...
Let it go. I didn't get hurt that badly.
And it's not even Hanazono's fault to begin with.
As captain of the basketball team, please accept
my apologies for all that's happened lately.
There's no excuse for our actions.
I'm deeply sorry.
Rikukaikuu doko ni ikou
Ahiru no Sora
Kimi o sasoitai na
Monogatari wa hajima tterunda
Okubyou kaze mo recycle
Mayotteru senaka oshite
Give and go! Isogou
Mogutteita honou ga kaodashite
Kakusenai no sa yume ni mita yume
Tobenai tsubasa demo
Bokura wa habataite sora o kanjitai
Naritai jibun ni naritai
Ima dekinai koto mo ashita wa wakannai ze
Waru agaki shiyou
Happy go ducky!
The Duck and the Kite
What the hell is that guy's problem?!
I totally HATE jerks like him with a burning passion!
You're bouncing off the walls more than usual.
Of course!
Momoharu said that if we caused any problems
then the team would be disbanded!
If people start thinking that jerk is on the basketball team,
then we'll have major problems!
Well, you're right about that.
That all aside, what's going on with Chiaki?
He's been crying like a baby since yesterday.
Well...
Yay!
Apparently two girls showed up
wanting to be the team managers.
Yo.
But they took one look at Chiaki's face
and nope'd right out of here.
Huh?
Did we always have a ball like this lying around?
It looks almost ancient.
Oh. I'm pretty sure it belongs to that Kite guy.
He left it behind yesterday.
Whoa. It's really suffered a lot of wear and tear.
Wait, is this because of...?
I can't see, it's too dark.
That's what you're looking for, right?
It seems like you've used that ball for a long time.
And without being on an actual court much.
I was always told never to use
real leather balls outdoors.
Because it would get all messed up, just like yours.
But since I had no court to play on,
mine ended up in a similar state.
I think... you had the same problem, didn't you?
You want to play basketball, right?
So you should apologize to everyone
and ask to officially join the team!
Mind your own damn business.
I hardly even felt that punch.
Go right ahead and beat me up all you want,
but please make a genuine apology
to Yasuhara and the girls' volleyball team.
Screw that!
I ain't wasting my time
playing basketball with you chumps.
There's nothing I hate more than sappy,
team bonding bullshit.
I only care 'bout two things:
the ball and the basket, that's all.
Don't ever bother me with this crap again, shrimp.
Ow! Damn! It really hurts! Shit!
Oh yeah? You managed to deal
with that mess from yesterday?
Yeah. I made a formal apology to them.
You're being too much of a suck up, Momoharu.
All you needed to do was tell them
that punk isn't on our team.
Right, Tinytown?
You don't want to have anything to do
with that jackass either, right?
Well, I...
I get the sense that Kite guy
isn't as much of a thug as he seems.
Huh? What kind of crap are you spouting now?
No, it's just...
I'm getting real sick of all your crazy talk.
E-excuse me!
That guy from yesterday is in the gym again!
What the hell happened here?
Hey, Yabuuchi. What's going on?
No idea. It was already over by the time we got here.
What is your problem?
Wait, Sora!
Just what the hell are you thinking?!
Momoharu, Yasuhara, and everyone else on the team
finally came around to playing basketball with me!
We just managed to form ourselves into a proper team!
Is causing trouble for literally everyone
the only thing you know how to do?!
That shit ain't my problem.
Damn you!
Madoka...?
Stop acting like a spoiled brat!
Everybody else around here plays by the rules!
You're a basketball player, too, right?
Then you should know how to follow
the basic rules at the very least!
And if you can't manage that,
then just quit and never come back!
You've got some real guts, girl.
What is this all about?
I just became your advisor and already a fight?
I can't believe the nerve of you boys.
Satsuki, the teacher who keeps the student body in line.
THIS is who we got for an advisor?
Well, I got saddled with a duty
I wasn't very intent on fulfilling.
I would actually prefer if the team
was disbanded right away.
I take it this was the basketball team's fault?
Mr. Satsuki it isn't what you-
I have no interest in hearing what your excuses are.
The condition you agreed to
was immediate disbandment for any trouble caused.
And this is a clear case of fighting on school grounds.
Thus, the basketball team is disbanded.
Disbanded?!
Wait a damn minute!
How the hell does that work?!
That jerk pulled this stunt all on his own!
He isn't even a member of the basketball team, anyway!
Oh?
You're telling me that he has
no connection to the team at all?
Is that how you're handling this, Captain?
That's not really...
What's the problem, Momoharu?!
Why don't you just make it clear?!
You know this guy isn't one of us!
Payphone
Seriously? She's calling again?
Give me a break.
Hey, what's up? It's me.
Whaddya want now?
Don't fuck with me, shrimp.
Pick it up.
This isn't the time to be off in your own world!
Our entire team is in serious trouble because of you!
I fucking told you to pick it up!
Enough!
Kenji Natsume.
Your suspension from school was barely lifted yesterday.
And you'll get even worse for this mess.
Be ready to get expelled.
As agreed, the basketball team will be disband-
Hold up.
I ain't on the basketball team.
Huh?
Don't group me with these losers.
They're below me.
Say that again, bitch!
I see.
So you're to blame for everything, then?
Damn right.
It seems you've avoided the worst-case scenario.
How fortunate for you, Hanazono.
BOYS'
BASKETBALL
TEAM
Seriously? We didn't get disbanded?
Shucks, I was already thinking about
which club to join next.
What's your problem with our team?
I mean, come on.
There aren't even any cute girls
who want to be our manager.
Oh, jeez. Of all the problems we have, that ain't one.
Well, in any case, we can at least start using the court now.
All's well that ends well, right Momoharu?
Whatever.
Somebody woke up on the wrong side
of the bed this morning.
Cut him some slack. I think Momoharu was starting
to take a real interest in that Kite punk.
The good news is, we can get back
to playing basketball again now!
Hey, Chuckie.
Do you know who those guys were that Kite beat up?
One of them was a senior named Nishiwaki.
And I'm pretty sure the rest
were all part of the group he runs with.
What are you asking for?
No reason. Just curious.
Do you think that guy is really going to get expelled?
The whole thing just didn't sit right with me.
I don't think there's anything for you
to feel guilty about, Madoka.
Well sure, except...
...I slapped him across the face.
If you hadn't stepped in,
then I would have done it myself!
I had an ace up my sleeve.
A secret attack, the "Execution Punch!"
Was that it...?
Anyway, that guy is just a big coward!
It's why he lashes out!
He deserved a good smack or two!
But still...
...he took responsibility
and admitted to everything he did.
He may be a lot of things, but a coward isn't one of them.
Huh?
Madoka! Homeroom is about to start!
Yeah, okay.
See ya.
Madoka...?
Madoka seemed kind of cold towards me today.
I can't remember, did I do something to upset her?
I know for sure that I haven't done anything extreme
like when I ran around the gym buck naked...
I know that ringtone...
It's him!
Hey, is that you Juri?
How many times do I hafta tell you?
Don't waste your money on the payphone
and buy some candy instead.
Nuh-uh!
I want to hear your voice way more
than I want any candy!
Dummy. You know that's just wasting your allowance.
It's okay. 'Cuz I get lots and lots of it!
Is mom doin' okay?
Yeah.
She's pretty worried about you, Big Bro.
And dad is, too.
I don't want to hear anything about him...
Big Bro, be careful not to break your phone this time.
Oops, thanks.
Say, Big Bro?
What is it?
When can I see you again?
Well, this year's inter-high tournament
is gonna be held over there.
In Hiroshima.
I'll see you this summer. Just wait.
Okay! I'm waiting!
Sorry to keep you waiting, Juri!
Dad's coming this way, so I'm hanging up!
Who were you calling?
Don't tell me it was...
Th-the National Weather Service to get the forecast!
I need you to understand.
Kenji isn't a part of our family anymore.
Don't call him ever again, okay?
Okay...
Another goddamn fight?!
Kenji! Just how long are you going to keep
dragging my good name through the mud?!
What does it matter? You ain't my real father, anyway.
Just piss off.
Hey! Get back here!
Big Bro!
Can you believe it, Juri?
I'm not the brightest,
but there's a high school basketball coach who actually sent an invite just for me.
What's a "coach"?
An important person.
There's a really strong school in central Hiroshima and their coach is
saying he wants me to play for them.
Wow!
Just you watch.
Once I get into high school,
I'll make sure the whole
country learns my name at the inter-high tourney!
Inter-high! I'm so excited!
Kenji.
You're a young adult going into high school now.
It's been decided that you're going
to be moving this spring,
to live with one of your aunts in Kanagawa.
The inter-high, huh?
It's still so far away...
No, it's really not.
If someone important is waiting for you,
then why aren't you taking it seriously?
Are you stupid or what?
There's no way a team like yours can go to th-
We can!
At the very least, I truly believe that we can.
No, we WILL! Without a doubt!
It's impossible and you know it!
Playing basketball with losers like them is waste of time.
I'd make more progress just doing it on my own!
Then tell me...
Why did you tell that person on the phone
to wait for you?
You shouldn't be making promises
that you can't even keep!
It's not something you would understand.
But I do.
Yeah! I'll be waiting!
We're in the same situation.
I'm going to reach the inter-high tournament,
along with everyone on the Kuzu High team!
Just how deep in the boonies
have you been playing basketball?
Whatever. I'm getting expelled anyway.
I'll give you a test. Then you'll realize
just how goddamn helpless you actually are.
One-on-one.
Come learn what it's really like
to play at the national level.
One-on-one.
The rules are simple.
If you manage to take the ball from me, you win.
I won't take a step outside of this circle.
You're free to move however you want.
All right.
Then in the event that I win,
you join our team and swear
to uphold that promise you made on the phone!
How dumb can you get?
I'm gonna be expelled either wa-
No excuses, just swear to me!
Fine, whatever.
All I have to do is get the ball.
The rules he set actually work in my favor.
I'll match his pace.
And then in the instant that the ball leaves his hand...
...I'll strike!
I didn't even see him move!
You stand no chance. You're too slow.
Ready to quit?
I will NEVER be a quitter!
All talk and no game. We done yet?
I haven't been able to lay even a finger on the ball...
This tiny circle is starting to feel like
we're playing on a full court!
His playstyle is completely different from how he looks!
It's so smooth and fancy,
and requires more than just speed!
I can understand now why Momoharu was so invested
in watching this guy play on the court!
The way that he plays basketball...
...is just so captivating!
Is that it?
Your skills hardly amount to anything, as you can see.
He's on a completely different level than me.
There's no way I'm going to get that ball...
Don't give up!
You've almost got it!
Hey, short dude! I believe in you!
Just leave it to me!
I'll get that ball no matter what!
Just give it up already.
This will never end.
Not yet.
Just a little more...
...and then that ball is mine!
I almost got it!
Whoops!
Just a little more and that ball is mine, dad!
That was a close one.
It's right here!
Just a little more...!
Come on! Come on!
Too bad, ya dummy!
Passes are unfair!
So hey, dad?
What?
About my birthday...
Next week, yeah? Ask for whatever ya want!
Okay, then... I want a legit basketball!
One of those fancy ones made from real leather!
Our family doesn't have that kind of money! Ya dummy!
I know that! I just wanted to see what you'd say!
I swear, nobody on Earth ever has as much fun
as you playing basketball.
Yamanaka
I did it!
It's mine!
W-wait a sec!
That one didn't count!
I won! I won!
Right, everybody?
Did you see? Wasn't I amazing?
I'm the winner! I won and that means...
...I forgot.
What were we betting on again?
He's so stupid. His head must be totally empty.
Is that you, Natsume?
Mr. Satsuki...
We just finished having a school staff meeting
a few minutes ago.
Your punishment has been decided.
You actually are going to be expelled.
As if there was anything else.
Peace out, shrimp.
Keep practicing.
Please wait a moment, Mr. Satsuki.
What is it?
In regards to yesterday's fight at the gym,
there was one important thing that I lied to you about.
The one who beat up all those guys... it was actually me!
Nobody's buying that, you dumbass!
Why do you do this, Yasuhara?
Because your lies always make everything
so damn complicated!
What exactly are you boys trying to get at here?
Not much.
I won't deny that a fight happened.
But you know,
you should at least find out what caused it.
We brought along the guys
that got beat up by him yesterday.
They'll tell you what happened,
and I think it'll make you reconsider his punishment.
You guys...
Doredake sora o miagetatte
Boku wa tobenai to kimi wa itta
Ato nankai te o nobaseba
Todoku no darou to naita yoru
Nigedasu koto ni nareteitte
Sore ga yowasa dato shitta ano hi
Hajimeyou mata, kyou kara
Taisetsu na mono wa itsudemo soba ni atta
Bokura wa itsumo hitori janai donna toki mo
Toberu sa doko made mo kimi wa
Dare yori tataku tataku habataite
Nagashita namida no kazu dake
Tsuyoku narunda
Tsubasa hiroge sekai o megutte
Dare mo shiranai mirai o sagasou
Zutto, zutto, zutto
Aruite yukou saa, issho ni
Ahiru no Sora
Next Time: Kite, His Ball
and the Team's Pain
Next time: "Kite, His Ball, and the Team's Pain."